Rindra Josia Rakotonarivo

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

rrindrajosia@gmail.com | Portfolio | Github | Linkedin | Twitter

SUMMARY

A full-stack developer that can work cross-functionally between the front-end and back-end while managing multiple projects ranging in priority levels. Proven experience developing customer-focused websites using Ruby on Rails, PHP, CSS, HTML, ES6. Designed and developed web applications across multiple APIs and Databases.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3.

Back-End: PHP, Ruby, Rails, MySQL.

 $\textbf{Tools \& Methods} : \textit{Git}, \textit{GitHub}, \textit{Heroku}, \textit{Netlify}, \textit{Mobile/Responsive Development}, \textit{RSpec}, \textit{TDD}, \textit{Chrome Development}, \textit{RSpec}, \textit{Chrome Development}, \textit{C$

Dev Tools.

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring.

EXPÉRIENCE

Full-stack developer for 6+ years working on a variety of projects. Below some of the best projects have been highlighted:

Ministry of Population (Madagascar) Responsible for databases and software

April 2011 - Dec 2019

- Website redesign that has increased the Ministry's reputation and awareness.
 Link: www.population.gov.mg.
- GIS web application which has helped decision-makers locate the installation of infrastructures (i.e., water supply).

Microverse May 2020 – Dec 2020

Mentor (Volunteer)

- Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE March 2020 - Dec 2020

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

AMITY UNIVERSITY (INDIA)

Dec 2010 - Dec 2011

Postgraduate Diploma in IT (E-Learning)

- HTML, CSS, PHP, C#, JEE and JavaScript.
- Oracle, MySQL.